CÉSAR NÚÑEZ HUAMÁN

 $+51990992899 \Leftrightarrow Lima, Perú$

ca.nunezhuaman@gmail.com \$ linkedin.com/in/cesar-nunez-huaman

Bachelor in Economics with a concentration in economics for the public sector and with more than 5 years of experience in consulting in public policies, social policies and economics. I have studies in qualitative and quantitative methods applied to the evaluation of social programs and public management. I have experience in database management in STATA, R and Python applied to social sciences.

EDUCATION

Licensed Economist, Universidad del Pacífico - UP

2020

Thesis: The effect of teacher training on pedagogical practices and learning. Available here.

Bachelor in Economics, Universidad del Pacífico - UP

2013 - 2017

GPA: 15.64/20.0 — Ranked: 6 out of 68 — Concentration in economics for the public sector.

COURSES AND SPECIALIZATION PROGRAMS

MicroMasters Program on Data, Economics and Development Policy, Massachusetts Institute of Technology - MIT

2022 - Present

Coursework: Designing and Running Randomized Evaluations, Data Analysis for Social Scientists, Foundations of Development Policy. Currently enrolled in the program. Already approved 3 out of 6 courses of the program.

Specialization in Data Science for Social Sciences and Public Management, Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú - PUCP 2022 - 2023

Coursework: Python Intermediate, Introduction to Machine Learning, Advanced Applied Econometrics. Currently enrolled in the program. Already approved 8 out of 10 courses of the program.

Governance, Political Management and Public Management Program, Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú - PUCP 2020 - 2021

Completed with satisfactory approval by the Development Bank of Latin America (CAF) and PUCP.

Social Programs Evaluation, Grupo de Análisis para el Desarrollo - GRADE Completed with the certificate of "Outstanding Approval".

2019

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Analyst

Analyst

Jul 2020 - Present

Videnza Consultores

Lima, Perú

- Coordinate, design, plan and lead the execution of more than 15 consultancy projects and proposals, which include the analysis and systematization of primary and secondary data.
- Lead the design and implementation of three topics at the "Observatorio del Bicentenario", a repository of national and regional statistics launched in October 2021 with more than 150 indicators. Available here.
- Successfully collaborate with the publication of 2 books under the initiative "Propuestas del Bicentenario" which presents public policy proposals to face the main challenges of Peru.

Consejo Privado de Competitividad (CPC)

Jul 2019 - Jun 2020

Lima, Perú

- Lead the annually and quarterly actualization of the Regional Public Management Index (IRGP) which measures the performance of regional and local public management at the 25 regions of Perú and it was published on Diario Gestión in several times. Available here.
- Provide follow-up to the public policy proposals, which more than 69 percent have got into the National Competitiveness and Productivity Plan, national laws, and other areas of the public sector.
- Analise and develop public policy evidence-based proposals and develop the Competitiveness Report 2020 and 2021. I've contributed to Infrastructure, Health System, Business Environment and Logistics chapters.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Project assistant

AC Pública, APOYO Consultoría's subsidiary

Jan 2018 - Jul 2019 *Lima*, *Perú*

- I actively participated in the development and approval of the National Agrarian Innovation Policy and the National Agrarian Innovation Plan.
- Perform management and planning consulting projects run, in terms of time, scope and resources. Also, execute the project's activities and tasks.
- Successfully lead the updating of supply and demand estimates for 12 regional airports' Master Development Plans.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching assistant, Universidad del Pacífico - UP

2016 - 2023

In the following courses and semesters:

- Introduction to Microeconomics (Aug 2016 Dec 2018)
- Microeconomics I (Aug 2017 Dec 2017)
- Introduction to Macroeconomics (Aug 2019 Dec 2023)

LANGUAGES

Spanish NativeEnglish Advanced

INFORMATIC SOFTWARE AND PROGRAMMING

Microsoft Excel Advanced
Eviews Advanced
STATA Advanced
R Intermediate
Python Intermediate
Atlas.ti Intermediate

PUBLICATIONS

During my professional experience I have contributed to the following publications:

Bustamante, P. (2022) La necesaria viabilidad social para el desarrollo sostenible de la minería. En L. M. Castilla et al (2022), Propuestas del Bicentenario: Rutas para el desarrollo regional (págs. 215-241). Lima: Penguin Random House. Available here.

Bustamante, P., Núñez, C. (2023) Generación de valor, rentabilidad social y conflictividad en el entorno de proyectos mineros en Perú. Documento de Discusión. Lima: Banco Interamericano de Desarrollo. Available here.

Castilla, L. M. (2021) Reactivación Económica para el crecimiento sostenido. En L. M. Castilla et al (2021), Propuestas del Bicentenario: Rutas para un país en desarrollo (págs. 29-64). Lima: Penguin Random House. Available here.

Castilla, L. M. (2022) Encadenamientos productivos y desarrollo regional: el caso de la minería.. En L. M. Castilla et al (2022), Propuestas del Bicentenario: Rutas para el desarrollo regional (págs. 215-241). Lima: Penguin Random House. Available here.

Castilla, L. M., Seinfeld, J., von Hese, M., Besich, N. (2021) *Introducción*. En L. M. Castilla et al (2021), *Propuestas del Bicentenario: Rutas para un país en desarrollo* (págs. 29-64). Lima: Penguin Random House. Available here.

Consejo Privado de Competitividad. (2019). Informe de Competitividad 2020. Lima: Consejo Privado de Competitividad. Available here.

Consejo Privado de Competitividad. (2020). Informe de Competitividad 2021. Lima: Consejo Privado de Competitividad. Available here.

RELEVANT CONSULTANCY PROJECTS

Formulation of the National Agrarian Innovation Policy and Plan (Jan 2018 - Jan 2019). Consultancy within the framework of the National Agricultural Innovation Program whose purpose was to develop a situational diagnosis of agricultural innovation in Peru and formulate the National Policy and Plan for Agricultural Innovation.

Analysis of the situation of children and adolescents in Peru for UNICEF Peru (Jul 2020 - Feb 2021). Consultancy to develop the analysis of the situation of children and adolescents for the new Cooperation Program between the United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF) and the Peruvian State. This analysis focused on the rights to health, education, social protection, and protection from violence. You can access the executive summary here.

Research project on the performance of public officials in charge of general procurement processes in Peru (Jul 2020 - Jan 2021). Consultancy to identify strategies that contribute to improving the public procurement process of medical supplies. Specifically, an intervention based on behavioral sciences was designed and an impact evaluation plan was designed to measure the results of said intervention.

Consultancy for the measurement of results of the study of interventions to support public procurement processes in Peru (Mar 2021 - Jan 2022). Consultancy to implement and monitor the intervention designed to improve public procurement processes for medical supplies, as well as to perform an impact evaluation. The intervention allowed for a higher purchase award ratio and a reduction in the unit prices of purchases of medical supplies.

Consultancy for the preparation of a discussion document on the generation of value in the environment of mining projects in Peru and its implications in the conflict (Nov 2021 - Feb 2022). Consultancy to identify the conditions and characteristics necessary for the generation of value in environments where mining activities are carried out; as well as to identify the relationship that exists between these characteristics and social conflict.

Estimation of the fiscal and economic impact of the energy transition in Peru (Aug 2022 - Dec 2022). Consulting to develop the estimate of the fiscal and economic impact of the energy transition of the Peruvian electricity matrix, in terms of loss of gas royalty collection.

Technical Assistance for the integration of the processes that make up the Multiannual Investment Programming and the Multiannual Budgetary Programming in terms of investments (Sep 2022 - Jan 2023). Consulting to prepare a proposal to optimize the automation and interrelation between the processes of the Multiannual Investment Programming and the Multiannual Budgetary Programming of public investments.

Consulting for the systematization of public management experiences or practices of the USAID Project: Institutional Strengthening of DEVIDA (FID) (Apr 2023 - Sep 2023). Consulting for the systematization of five public management experiences of the FID Project. The experiences prioritized by the FID Project were: i) strengthening of contracting management, ii) strengthening of producer organizations through the VEO tool, iii) promotion of obtaining financing in community organizations, iv) strengthening of investment management in municipalities and v) obtaining additional municipal resources for public investment. This work involved a documentary review and qualitative field work to identify strengths and opportunities for improvement in the five experiences prioritized by the FID Project.

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- EvalYouth Global Mentoring Program (EY-GMP) 2020-2021. The EY-GMP is an initiative to support novice evaluators and young professionals to become skilled and trusted professionals who can confidently undertake evaluation roles in their communities and countries.
- Impacta! Young people for public management 2019-2020. Impacta is a non-profit civil association, directed and made up of young people convinced that to achieve the full development of a country it is necessary to have solid, transparent public institutions capable of responding efficiently to the needs of its citizens.